http://www.nla.gov.au/about-this-site/privacy

Privacy | National Library of Australia
Jump to content
Enjoy a CovidSafe visit to the National Library. Read more...
Petherick Reading Room
Copies and interlibrary loansCopies and interlibrary loans for individuals
Australian Libraries Gateway
Australian Interlibrary Resource Sharing (ILRS)
Privacy
The purpose of this statement is to let users of this website know what information is collected about them when they visit this site, how this information is used and if it is disclosed.
This statement has been prepared in accordance with the Federal Privacy Commissioner's Guidelines for Federal and ACT Government World Wide Websites.
Find out more in our Privacy Policy.
Please see the Trove Privacy Statement for information on how the Library manages privacy and personal information relating to Trove users, and library material available through Trove.
Recording your visit
When you look at NLA websites, we make a record of your visit and log the following information for statistical purposes:
your server address
your top level domain name (for example .com, .gov, .au, .uk)
date and time of your visit to the site
pages you accessed and documents you downloaded
the previous site you visited
type of browser you used.
No attempt will be made to identify individual users or their browsing activities except in the event that it is reasonably necessary for the enforcement of criminal law. In the case of the latter, we will comply with the Australian Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) regarding the limits and protocols associated with disclosure of personal information.
Some sites use 'cookies' to track a particular user's access to a site. Cookies are not used on this site to gather information about users interactions with this website with two exceptions:
Within specific web-based applications, such as our online surveys, where they are used for session management purposes only.
Google Analytics uses first-party cookies and JavaScript code to help analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to Google. Google will use this information for the purpose of compiling reports on website activity and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage.
You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser.
Recording your email address
We will only record your email address if you communicate with us. It will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it (for example, in relation to the administration of Trove or another Library service). Your email address will only be used or disclosed for another purpose with your consent, if authorised or required by law, or otherwise in accordance with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).
Collecting personal information
From time to time we will use electronic forms on this site to gather personal information for purposes directly related to a function or activity of the Library. When we do so we will let you know the purpose for which the information is being collected (including if the information is to be published), and the legal authority for the collection if it is authorised or required by or under law.
We will not collect or solicit personal information via this site which would be unlawful, unnecessary or unrelated to the functions or activities of the Library, or unfair or unreasonably intrusive.
Because there are risks associated with using the internet as a transmission medium, when we use electronic forms to collect information, where practicable, we will also provide you with other options for providing the information - for example, a paper form and mailing address and a telephone contact.
Credit card details collected via electronic forms on this site are encrypted for transmission using secure server technologies and are only made accessible to staff members authorised to complete the transaction.
Publishing personal information
We will only publish personal information on this site if it has been collected for this purpose with your knowledge or if you have consented to the disclosure. When giving such consent you should be aware that information published on this site is accessible to millions of users from all over the world, that it will be indexed by search engines and that it may be copied and used by any web user. This means that, once the information is published on this site, we will have no control over its subsequent use and disclosure.
About us
Fellowships, Scholarships and GrantsCommunity Heritage GrantsProjects funded by CHG
Guidelines and application form
Grant recipientsCommunity Heritage Grants Recipients 2019
Community Heritage Grants Recipients 2018
Community Heritage Grants Recipients 2017
Community Heritage Grants Recipients 2016
Significance assessments
Preservation needs assessments
Conservation activities and collection management
Useful resourcesPreservation and Collection Management Training Workshops 2018
Preservation and Collection Management Training Workshops 2017
Preservation and Collection Management Training Workshops 2016
Contact us
2019 Community Heritage Grants Assessment Report
Fellowships and ScholarshipsNational Library of Australia FellowshipsNational Library of Australia Fellows
Creative FellowshipsCreative Arts FellowshipCreative Arts Fellows
National Folk FellowshipNational Folk Fellows
Asia Study Grants2020 Asia Study Grant recipients
2019 Asia Study Grant recipients
2018 Asia Study Grant recipients
2011-2017 Japan Study Grant recipients
2008-2010 Japan Study Grant recipients
Summer ScholarshipsSummer ScholarsSummer Scholars 2011-2015
Summer Scholars 2006-2010
Summer Scholars 2002-2005
Past FellowshipsHarold White FellowshipsHarold White Fellows 2011-2014
Harold White Fellows 2001-2010
Harold White Fellows 1991-2000
Harold White Fellows 1986-1990
Japan FellowshipsJapan Fellows
Corporate documentsAnnual ReportsAnnual Report 2014 - 2015
Annual Report 2013 - 2014
Annual Report 2012 - 2013
Annual Report 2011 - 2012
Charter of Library's Audit Committee
Corporate PlansCorporate Plan 2020-2021National Library of Australia 2030
Collect
Connect
Collaborate
Capability
Operating context
Risk management
Corporate Plan 2019-2020Collect
Connect
Capability and risk management
Digital Library Infrastructure Replacement (DLIR)DLIR Program details
Enterprise Agreement
Executive Remuneration
Freedom of informationFreedom of information disclosure log
Information Publication SchemeAgency plan for the National Library of Australia
Policy and PlanningBorrowing material for Exhibitions
Code of conduct for readers and visitors
Collecting Strategy
Collection description policy
Collection development policyIntroduction
Principles
How We Collect
What We Collect
Selective Collecting: Overseas Publications
Collection digitisation policy
Collection disaster planPart 1: Disaster preparedness and prevention policy
Part 2: Disaster actions
Copyright position statements
Digital preservation policy
Disability Framework
Environmental policy
Events and education policy
Exhibitions Loans Policy
Exhibitions policy
Guidelines for the discard and retention of library material
Indexed List of File TitlesJan-Jun 2020 List of File Titles
Jul-Dec 2019
Jan-Jun 2019
Jul-Dec 2018
Jan-Jun 2018
Jul-Dec 2017
Jan-Jun 2017
Jul-Dec 2016
Onsite Volunteer Program policy
Policy on the illumination of collection material on display
Preservation policy
Privacy PolicyCCTV footage privacy notice
Publications policy
Social media policy
Social media strategy 2013-2014
StandardsAustralian METS Profile<div> TYPE attribute vocabulary
Australian Sound Recording METS Profile
Digitisation guidelinesImage capture standards
Technology Roadmap
Visitor access to and use of, medications and other personal medical equipment in the Library
Policy and planning
Portfolio Budget Statements
Privacy Impact Assessment Register
Public Interest Disclosures
Staff papers'Oh, you wanted us to preserve that?!' Statements of preservation intent for the NLA's digital collection
'To Elevate the Tone of Moral and Intellectual Attainment': the Braidwood Literary Institute and its Subscribers, 1858-1862
A new mandate for the digital age: implementing electronic legal deposit at the National Library of Australia
AskNow chat reference: trendsetter service bows out
Collaboration Strategies for Digital Collections: The Australian Experience
Collaboration across the collecting sectors
Collected Content / Distributed Meanings
Collecting Government Web Content at the National Library of Australia
Creating a vision for mobile service delivery
Defining File Format Obsolescence: A Risky Journey
Designing Metadata for Resource Discovery
Developing Trove; the policy and technical challenges
Developing a rights management system for the National Library of Australia's collections
DigCCurr 2009 Digital Curation Tools and Demos II - Mediapedia and Prometheus
Digging deep in Trove: Success, challenge and uncertainty
Digital Best Practice: a Library Viewpoint
Digital library economics: international perspectives -The Australian perspective
Digital preservation for ongoing access
Disaster Preparedness at the National Library of Australia
Easy as ABC - A triumph of re-usable metadata
Explaining Pres Actions: a Working Document
Exploring the Roles of Digitisation and Microfilming in Preserving Australian Newspapers for Permanent Access
Facing the Challenge of Web Archives Preservation Collaboratively
From portals to platforms: building new frameworks for user engagement
Getting the whole picture: Finding a common language between digital preservation and conservation
How to utilise Trove in your organisation
I Say Emulate; He Says Migrate - Are Emulation or Migration Feasible Preservation Strategies?
Identifying Researchers Using People Australia
Impact of technology on archival programs: the National Library of Australia
Implementing Digital Preservation Techniques into Next-Gen Operating Systems
Internet Content as Research Data: challenges and options for collecting and preserving
Jean Whyte Memorial Lecture
Libraries Australia Document Delivery: A System for a Variety of Users
Many Hands Make Light Work: Public Collaborative OCR Text Correction in Australian Historic Newspapers
Media Matters: developing processes for preserving digital objects on physical carriers at the National Library of Australia
Mediapedia: Managing the Identification of Media Carriers
Mediapedia: managing physical format media
Mobile Services Survey: summary findings
Music Australia: Building innovative partnerships for online access to music made, played and recorded in Australia
Now we’re getting somewhere – adventures in Trans Tasman interlending
PANDORA past, present and future - national web archiving in Australia
Powered by Trove: Opportunities and Challenges for Queensland Libraries
Preserve or Preserve Not, There is No Try: some dilemmas relating to Personal Digital Archiving
Preserving Access: Making More Informed 'Guesses' About What Works
Prometheus: managing the Ingest of Media Carriers
RESTafarian-ism at the NLA
Reading Locally, Learning Globally: creating a universal experience – a National Library view
Relevance ranking of results from MARC-based catalogues: from guidelines to implementation exploiting structured metadata
Resource Description and Access
Resource Description and Access: Structure, Content and the Development Process
Resource sharing in Australia: 'Find' and 'Get' in Trove - Making 'Getting' better
Setting a New Standard in Resource Description and Access
Shooting to Computing
Singing for their supper: Trove, Australian newspapers and the crowd
Single Business Discovery Project
The Australian METS Profile – A Journey about Metadata
The Australian Newspaper Plan (ANPLAN)
Those Mad Men from the Antipodes: Presentation Intent at the National Library of Australia
Trends in Use of the Pandora Archive
Trove and the world
Trove: Bringing Australian resources to Australian
Trove: More than a treasure? How finding information just became easier
Trove: The first year January 2010 - January 2011
Trove: staging of a social media pilot
Volunteering – maximising the benefits for all
Web archiving in a Web 2.0 world
What is the Mediapedia?
‘If a tree falls in the forest’: recording and sharing digital preservation knowledge at the NLA
‘Improving organisational performance through visitor feedback’
State of the Service Report
Statements of expectations and intent
Jobs at the LibraryCurrent vacancies
Information for applicantsStaff engagement
Temporary employment register
Workplace diversity
Indigenous employmentAboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Employment Strategy 2013–2018
Indigenous employee profiles
Indigenous community connections
Publishing guidelines
Who we areOrganisational structure
Library CouncilChair The Honourable Dr Brett Mason
Deputy Chair Ms Janet Hirst
Director-General and Executive Member Dr Marie-Louise Ayres
Member Mr Julian Leeser MP
Contracts for current reporting period
Contracts for previous reporting periodsSenate Order for entity contracts listing relating to the period 1 July 2017 - 30 June 2018
Senate Order for entity contracts listing relating to the period 1 July 2018 - 30 June 2019
Senate Order for entity contracts listing relating to the period 1 January 2017 - 31 December 2017
Senate Order for entity contracts listing relating to the period 1 July 2016 - 30 June 2017
Senate Order for entity contracts listing relating to the period 1 July 2018 to 30 June 2019
About this siteWebsite accessibility
Copyright for this website
Privacy
Moderation statement
User feedback
Takedown requests
eBooks
Our buildingHeritage
Acknowledgement of Country
The National Library of Australia (NLA) acknowledges Australia’s First Nations Peoples – the First Australians – as the Traditional Owners and Custodians of this land and gives respect to the Elders – past and present – and through them to all Australian Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people.
Contact us
+61 (0)2 6262 1111Parkes PlaceCanberra ACT 2600AustraliaOpening hoursMore contact information
Connect Facebook Twitter Instagram Flickr YouTube More connections
QuicklinksJobs at the LibraryAwards and grantsCopies DirectLibraries AustraliaWebsites A–Z
